<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="_group__x_stream_buffer_set_trigger_level" xml:lang="en-US">
<title>xStreamBufferSetTriggerLevel</title>
<indexterm><primary>xStreamBufferSetTriggerLevel</primary></indexterm>

<para><link linkend="_stream__buffer_8h">stream_buffer.h</link></para>

<para><literallayout>
BaseType_t <link linkend="_stream__buffer_8h_1a28f0280587c76e71efeaa8f415ebde04">xStreamBufferSetTriggerLevel( StreamBufferHandle_t xStreamBuffer, size_t xTriggerLevel )</link>;
</literallayout></para>

<para>A stream buffer&apos;s trigger level is the number of bytes that must be in the stream buffer before a task that is blocked on the stream buffer to wait for data is moved out of the blocked state. For example, if a task is blocked on a read of an empty stream buffer that has a trigger level of 1 then the task will be unblocked when a single byte is written to the buffer or the task&apos;s block time expires. As another example, if a task is blocked on a read of an empty stream buffer that has a trigger level of 10 then the task will not be unblocked until the stream buffer contains at least 10 bytes or the task&apos;s block time expires. If a reading task&apos;s block time expires before the trigger level is reached then the task will still receive however many bytes are actually available. Setting a trigger level of 0 will result in a trigger level of 1 being used. It is not valid to specify a trigger level that is greater than the buffer size.</para>

<para>A trigger level is set when the stream buffer is created, and can be modified using <link linkend="_stream__buffer_8h_1a28f0280587c76e71efeaa8f415ebde04">xStreamBufferSetTriggerLevel()</link>.</para>

<para>
                <formalpara>
                    <title>
Parameters</title>
                    <para>
                    <table frame="all">
                        <tgroup cols="2" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <colspec colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colwidth="4*"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
<entry>xStreamBuffer</entry><entry>
<para>The handle of the stream buffer being updated.</para>
</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
<entry>xTriggerLevel</entry><entry>
<para>The new trigger level for the stream buffer.</para>
</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                    </para>
                </formalpara>
                <formalpara><title>Returns</title>

<para>If xTriggerLevel was less than or equal to the stream buffer&apos;s length then the trigger level will be updated and pdTRUE is returned. Otherwise pdFALSE is returned. </para>
</formalpara>
</para>
</section>
