<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="_group__v_task_get_info" xml:lang="en-US">
<title>vTaskGetInfo</title>
<indexterm><primary>vTaskGetInfo</primary></indexterm>

<para>task. h <literallayout>void <link linkend="_task_8h_1ac08c26d037d0dc685740eec9b2028715">vTaskGetInfo( TaskHandle_t xTask, TaskStatus_t *pxTaskStatus, BaseType_t xGetFreeStackSpace, eTaskState eState )</link>;</literallayout></para>

<para>configUSE_TRACE_FACILITY must be defined as 1 for this function to be available. See the configuration section for more information.</para>

<para>Populates a TaskStatus_t structure with information about a task.</para>

<para>
                <formalpara>
                    <title>
Parameters</title>
                    <para>
                    <table frame="all">
                        <tgroup cols="2" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <colspec colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colwidth="4*"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
<entry>xTask</entry><entry>
<para>Handle of the task being queried. If xTask is NULL then information will be returned about the calling task.</para>
</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
<entry>pxTaskStatus</entry><entry>
<para>A pointer to the TaskStatus_t structure that will be filled with information about the task referenced by the handle passed using the xTask parameter.</para>
</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                    </para>
                </formalpara>
                @xGetFreeStackSpace The TaskStatus_t structure contains a member to report the stack high water mark of the task being queried. Calculating the stack high water mark takes a relatively long time, and can make the system temporarily unresponsive - so the xGetFreeStackSpace parameter is provided to allow the high water mark checking to be skipped. The high watermark value will only be written to the TaskStatus_t structure if xGetFreeStackSpace is not set to pdFALSE;</para>

<para>
                <formalpara>
                    <title>
Parameters</title>
                    <para>
                    <table frame="all">
                        <tgroup cols="2" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <colspec colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colwidth="4*"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
<entry>eState</entry><entry>
<para>The TaskStatus_t structure contains a member to report the state of the task being queried. Obtaining the task state is not as fast as a simple assignment - so the eState parameter is provided to allow the state information to be omitted from the TaskStatus_t structure. To obtain state information then set eState to eInvalid - otherwise the value passed in eState will be reported as the task state in the TaskStatus_t structure.</para>
</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                    </para>
                </formalpara>
                Example usage: <literallayout>
void vAFunction( void )
{
TaskHandle_t xHandle;
TaskStatus_t xTaskDetails;

   // Obtain the handle of a task from its name.
   xHandle = xTaskGetHandle( &quot;Task_Name&quot; );

   // Check the handle is not NULL.
   <link linkend="__free_r_t_o_s_8h_1a228c70cd48927d6ab730ed1a6dfbe35f">configASSERT( xHandle )</link>;

   // Use the handle to obtain further information about the task.
   vTaskGetInfo( xHandle,
                 &amp;xTaskDetails,
                 pdTRUE, // Include the high water mark in xTaskDetails.
                 eInvalid ); // Include the task state in xTaskDetails.
}
  </literallayout> </para>
</section>
