<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.6" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="group__x_task_create_restricted" kind="group">
    <compoundname>xTaskCreateRestricted</compoundname>
    <title>xTaskCreateRestricted</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>task. h <preformatted>
 BaseType_t xTaskCreateRestricted( TaskParameters_t *pxTaskDefinition, TaskHandle_t *pxCreatedTask );</preformatted></para>
<para>Only available when configSUPPORT_DYNAMIC_ALLOCATION is set to 1.</para>
<para>xTaskCreateRestricted() should only be used in systems that include an MPU implementation.</para>
<para>Create a new task and add it to the list of tasks that are ready to run. The function parameters define the memory regions and associated access permissions allocated to the task.</para>
<para>See xTaskCreateRestrictedStatic() for a version that does not use any dynamic memory allocation.</para>
<para><parameterlist kind="param"><parameteritem>
<parameternamelist>
<parametername>pxTaskDefinition</parametername>
</parameternamelist>
<parameterdescription>
<para>Pointer to a structure that contains a member for each of the normal <ref refid="tasks_8c_1ad138d9dda4709b10d711775fa40eb1a1" kindref="member">xTaskCreate()</ref> parameters (see the <ref refid="tasks_8c_1ad138d9dda4709b10d711775fa40eb1a1" kindref="member">xTaskCreate()</ref> API documentation) plus an optional stack buffer and the memory region definitions.</para>
</parameterdescription>
</parameteritem>
<parameteritem>
<parameternamelist>
<parametername>pxCreatedTask</parametername>
</parameternamelist>
<parameterdescription>
<para>Used to pass back a handle by which the created task can be referenced.</para>
</parameterdescription>
</parameteritem>
</parameterlist>
<simplesect kind="return"><para>pdPASS if the task was successfully created and added to a ready list, otherwise an error code defined in the file <ref refid="projdefs_8h" kindref="compound">projdefs.h</ref></para>
</simplesect>
Example usage: <preformatted>
// Create an TaskParameters_t structure that defines the task to be created.
static const TaskParameters_t xCheckTaskParameters =
{
    vATask,     // pvTaskCode - the function that implements the task.
    &quot;ATask&quot;,    // pcName - just a text name for the task to assist debugging.
    100,        // usStackDepth - the stack size DEFINED IN WORDS.
    NULL,       // pvParameters - passed into the task function as the function parameters.
    ( 1UL | portPRIVILEGE_BIT ),// uxPriority - task priority, set the portPRIVILEGE_BIT if the task should run in a privileged state.
    cStackBuffer,// puxStackBuffer - the buffer to be used as the task stack.

    // xRegions - Allocate up to three separate memory regions for access by
    // the task, with appropriate access permissions.  Different processors have
    // different memory alignment requirements - refer to the FreeRTOS documentation
    // for full information.
    {
        // Base address                 Length  Parameters
        { cReadWriteArray,              32,     portMPU_REGION_READ_WRITE },
        { cReadOnlyArray,               32,     portMPU_REGION_READ_ONLY },
        { cPrivilegedOnlyAccessArray,   128,    portMPU_REGION_PRIVILEGED_READ_WRITE }
    }
};

int main( void )
{
TaskHandle_t xHandle;

    // Create a task from the const structure defined above.  The task handle
    // is requested (the second parameter is not NULL) but in this case just for
    // demonstration purposes as its not actually used.
    xTaskCreateRestricted( &amp;xRegTest1Parameters, &amp;xHandle );

    // Start the scheduler.
    <ref refid="task_8h_1aaf9dca1065c60abdeb309d56ab7293cb" kindref="member">vTaskStartScheduler()</ref>;

    // Will only get here if there was insufficient memory to create the idle
    // and/or timer task.
    for( ;; );
}
   </preformatted></para>
<para>task. h <preformatted>
 void <ref refid="task_8h_1ad889595baff9faf9efe02f3696825409" kindref="member">vTaskAllocateMPURegions( TaskHandle_t xTask, const MemoryRegion_t * const pxRegions )</ref>;</preformatted></para>
<para>Memory regions are assigned to a restricted task when the task is created by a call to xTaskCreateRestricted(). These regions can be redefined using <ref refid="task_8h_1ad889595baff9faf9efe02f3696825409" kindref="member">vTaskAllocateMPURegions()</ref>.</para>
<para><parameterlist kind="param"><parameteritem>
<parameternamelist>
<parametername>xTask</parametername>
</parameternamelist>
<parameterdescription>
<para>The handle of the task being updated.</para>
</parameterdescription>
</parameteritem>
<parameteritem>
<parameternamelist>
<parametername>xRegions</parametername>
</parameternamelist>
<parameterdescription>
<para>A pointer to an MemoryRegion_t structure that contains the new memory region definitions.</para>
</parameterdescription>
</parameteritem>
</parameterlist>
Example usage: <preformatted>
// Define an array of MemoryRegion_t structures that configures an MPU region
// allowing read/write access for 1024 bytes starting at the beginning of the
// ucOneKByte array.  The other two of the maximum 3 definable regions are
// unused so set to zero.
static const MemoryRegion_t xAltRegions[ portNUM_CONFIGURABLE_REGIONS ] =
{
    // Base address     Length      Parameters
    { ucOneKByte,       1024,       portMPU_REGION_READ_WRITE },
    { 0,                0,          0 },
    { 0,                0,          0 }
};

void vATask( void *pvParameters )
{
    // This task was created such that it has access to certain regions of
    // memory as defined by the MPU configuration.  At some point it is
    // desired that these MPU regions are replaced with that defined in the
    // xAltRegions const struct above.  Use a call to <ref refid="task_8h_1ad889595baff9faf9efe02f3696825409" kindref="member">vTaskAllocateMPURegions()</ref>
    // for this purpose.  NULL is used as the task handle to indicate that this
    // function should modify the MPU regions of the calling task.
    vTaskAllocateMPURegions( NULL, xAltRegions );

    // Now the task can continue its function, but from this point on can only
    // access its stack and the ucOneKByte array (unless any other statically
    // defined or shared regions have been declared elsewhere).
}
   </preformatted> </para>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
